もうすぐ　ここに来る。
He'll be here soon.
ファイ・ブレインの世界にね。
To the world of the Phi Brain.
カイト…。
Kaito...
kimi no nounai he shinnyuu nemutteiru sukima ni
I infiltrate your brain while you're sleeping.
Baby, open the gate!
fukuzatsu sugi sekyuriti kakusareru to abakitaku naru
The security's too tough, but I want to expose what's hidden.
barabara ni chirabatteiru pasuwado wo hiroi atsume
I gather the pieces of the shattered password.
kakushin ni sematte iku sono shoutai wo misete
I get close to the core. Show me who you really are!
kantan ni kuria dekinai saki nante motto yomenai
I can't clear it easily. I can't even see what lies ahead.
kaidoku fukanou sumairu kikenna pazuru
Your indecipherable smile is a hazardous puzzle.
rokku sareta doa aru nara zutto tataite miru beki kazana hiraku wa
When you see a locked door, you should just hit it until a crack opens.
eien ni hodokenai nazo nanka wa nai
There's no mystery that lasts forever!
makiokosu, it's a supernova
I made it, it's a supernova!
tobikiri shigekitekina hirameki wo agemashou
Let's flash so bright it'd hurt!
Misskey-Misskey La-Tu-Ma
yume no naka it's a supernova
In my dreams, it's a supernova!
watashi wa sou brain diver
Yeah, I'm the brain diver!
kimi ga sagashi motometeru kotae ni nareru made
Until I can find the answer you're looking for...
Brain diver!
The One to Carry on His Will
（バロン）ジン。　ここに居たんだな。
Jin... So you were here.
（ジン）残りは　１，８４４京６，７４４兆
７３７億９４８万６，０７９手。
Only 184,467,447,379,486,079 moves remaining.
もう少しで解ける。
あと　もう少し。
I can solve it soon. Just a little longer.
ジン！　お前…。
Jin! What on Earth...
はぁ。
もう　いい。
It's okay.
お前は　もう十分に　頑張った。
もう　いいんだ。
You've worked hard enough. It's okay.
うっ。　これは罰だというのか。
神に触れようとした者への…。
Is this punishment? For the people who tried to reach God...
（ギャモン）１人で浸ってんじゃねえよ。
うっ。　ギャモン君。
Don't try to do it yourself.
Gammon?
隠し事は　もう　たくさんだ。
I've had enough with secrets.
今度こそ　全て
吐いてもらおうじゃねえか。
You're gonna tell me everything this time.
そいつは　一体　何者だ？
Who's this guy?
彼は…　真方ジン。
He's... Makata Jin.
私のただ一人の親友にして　かつて
最もファイ・ブレインに近づいた男です。
He was my best friend.
The man who got the closest to the Phi Brain.
（カイト）あれは…。
Is that...
あれが　神のパズルが解放された
未来だっていうのか？
Is that the future if the Divine Puzzle is released?
誰なんだ？　あいつは。
Who is that?
Kaito!
（ノノハ）カイト。
あっ！
ノノハか…　あっち行けよ。
Nonoha?
Leave me alone.
うん。　行ってほしかったら
勝負して。
勝負？！
If you want me to leave, then fight me.
Fight?
私が負けたら
もう　カイトには近づかない。
If I lose, I'll never come near you again.
ふ～ん。　いいぜ…　うっ。
Okay!
うりゃ…　うりゃ～！
あ～！
私の勝ち！
…って　パズル勝負じゃねえのかよ。
I win!
It wasn't a puzzle fight?
当たり前じゃん。
パズルで　私が勝てるはずないもん。
Of course not! I could never win in a puzzle challenge.
…ったく　アホか！
うん。　アホでもバカでも　結構。
Are you retarded?
So what if I am?
パズル解けなくたって　私には
私のできることがあるんだから。
Even if I can't solve puzzles, I'm good at other things.
ノノハ…。
私は　カイトから離れないから。
Nonoha...
I won't leave your side. Not in a million years.
絶対に離れないんだからね。
さあ　私が勝ったんだから
私の言うこと　聞け～！
And I won, so listen to me now!
（ソウジ）お取り込み中のところ
失礼するよ。
軸川先輩。
Sorry for interrupting when you're so busy...
Jikugawa!
カイト君　君に
見せたいものがあるんだ。
Kaito, there's something I'd like to show you.
これが　ＰＯＧの中枢？
This is the POG's backbone?
（キュービック）そう。
ここに到達するまでには→
Yeah. It required breaking through dozens of security puzzles to get to this point.
何重ものセキュリティー・パズルを
突破しなきゃならなかった。
But...
だけど…。
全部　キュービック君が解いてくれたよ。
Cubic solved it all.
あぁ？！
彼が　たった一人で　やったんだ。
He did it all alone.
カイト君のためにね。
はぁ。
For you, Kaito.
You're amazing, Cubie!
すごいじゃん　キューちゃん。
ま　まあ　僕の頭脳をもってすれば
これくらいのこと　当然だけどね。
W-Well, with my brains, it's only natural I can do this much!
キュービック。
ん？
Cubic...
ありがとな。
はぁ　うん！
Thanks.
さて　ここからは　ＰＯＧの
トップだけが知る　未知の領域だ。
This is the area only the POG's leaders know about.
君に　ＰＯＧと　神のパズルの
真実を知る覚悟はあるかい？
Are you prepared to know the truth behind the POG and the Divine Puzzle?
もちろんだ。
Of course!
ちょっと待って。　その前に教えて。
カイト　最近　一体　何を見たの？
Wait!
Before that, tell me...
What were you seeing recently?
Kaito?
ねえ　カイト…。
俺が見たのは　未来…。
I've seen the future.
未来？！
たぶん…　この世界の最期の姿だ。
The future?
Probably.
The way the world is going to end.
（アナ）世界の終わり。
The end of the world...
そんな…　未来が見えてたなんて！
But... the future?
しかも　世界の滅亡？！
And the end of the world?
これも　カイトの脳の思考速度が
超加速した結果なのかもしれない。
It may be the result of Kaito's brain overaccelerating.
でも　いくら何でも
そんなことは…。
But that's still...
ありうるよ。　それだけの力を
オルペウスの腕輪は秘めているからね。
It's possible. The Armband of Orpheus has that power.
もし　このまま誰かが
神の書を手に入れたら→
If someone obtains the Divine Revelations, that future will come. Jin said so.
あの未来に行きつく。
ジンが　そう言ってた。
誰かって　一体　誰？
Someone? Who?
Probably the mastermind of the POG, Count Pythagoras.
おそらく　ＰＯＧの総帥
ピタゴラス伯爵。
うっ。
神のパズルに取りつかれた男だ。
A man obsessed with the Divine Puzzle.
やはり　ルーク管理官も
ファイ・ブレインの子供でしたか…。
Chief Rook was a child of the Phi Brain as well.
ようやく見えてきましたよ。
ピタゴラス伯爵の本当の狙いが。
Now I can finally understand it.
I see what Count Pythagoras is truly after.
どういうことだ？！
あのルークの野郎も→
What do you mean? Is that Rook guy a contractor of the Armband of Orpheus as well?
オルペウスの腕輪の
契約者だっていうのかよ？
そう。　オルペウスの腕輪は
１つではありません。
Yes. There is more than one Armband.
世界各国で発見され→
They have been discovered all over the world. We can't even estimate the total number.
その正確な数は　いまだ
把握されていないのです。
１つじゃねえって。
More than one? First of all, who made all that crazy shit?
そもそも　一体　誰が　あんな
ベラボーなもん　作ったんだよ？
それを知る者も
もはや　誰もいません。
No one knows that anymore.
あぁ？
オルペウスの腕輪は発掘されたのです。
The Armbands of Orpheus have been discovered.
２，３００年前　我々
ＰＯＧの手によって　初めて。→
The first was found 2300 years ago... by us, the POG.
何者かが作り上げた　人間の脳を
極限まで活性化させる装置。
A device of unknown origin that amplifies human brain activity to its extremes.
それが　オルペウスの腕輪なのです。
That is the Armband of Orpheus.
その使用目的　製造方法は
一切不明。
We know nothing about their purpose or how they are manufactured.
しかし　いつしか　それは　神の書の
獲得という　究極の願いのために→
But with time, they turned into the keys of fulfilling any wish by acquiring the Divine Revelations.
利用されるようになりました。
ファイ・ブレインとなったギヴァーとソルヴァーが
己の持てる全ての力をぶつけ合う。
Givers and Solvers who became Phi Brains fight with all their power.
それこそが　神のパズルへの扉を開く
唯一無二の方法なのですから。
That is the only way to open the gate to the Divine Puzzle.
おい　つまり…。
そうです。　伯爵は→
Does that mean...
Yes. The Count intends to clash Chief Rook and Kaito.
カイト君とルーク管理官を
戦わせるつもりです。
He is trying to repeat the ritual that failed two years ago,
彼は　再び　繰り返そうと
しているのですよ。
２年前　自らとジンをもってしても
成しえなかった　あの儀式を。
when he and Jin attempted it.
ジン！
Jin!
（バロン）真方ジン。　彼もまた　ピタゴラス
伯爵によって運命を仕組まれた→
Makata Jin.
He was a contractor of an Armband. His life was toyed around with by the Count.
腕輪の契約者でした。
回想
（ジン）あっ！　解けたぜ　バロン。
I solved it, Baron.
回想
うっ。　これが　学園生活最後の
対決だってのに　また俺の負けか。
Even the last challenge of our student lives ends with me losing, huh?
回想
どんなパズルも
解いてしまうんだな。　ジンは。
You can solve any puzzle, Jin.
回想
何　弱気なこと　言ってんだよ。
Don't sound so timid.
回想
俺たち　これから
ＰＯＧに入るんだぜ。
We're gonna join the POG now!
あぁ。
回想
お前は　ギヴァーの頂点を目指せよ。
Yeah.
You should try to become the best Giver.
回想
俺は　ソルヴァーの
てっぺんに立ってやる。
And I'll be the best Solver.
回想
ソルヴァーの　てっぺん…。
ファイ・ブレインだ。
The best Solver, huh?
The Phi Brain. I'll become a Phi Brain.
回想
俺は　ファイ・ブレインになる。
そして　絶対に
回想
神のパズルを解いてやる。
And I'll solve the Divine Puzzle!
回想
（ピタゴラス伯爵）君たちを　ＰＯＧへ
迎え入れたわけは　他でもない。
I have accepted you into the POG for one reason.
神のパズルを解き　神の書を
回想
手に入れてくれたまえ。
Solve the Divine Puzzle and obtain the Divine Revelations.
回想
人類の新たなる
門出のために。　真方ジン。
For a new departure of mankind.
Makata Jin.
は　はい！
回想
（伯爵）君には期待している。
Y-Yes, sir!
I have high expectations of you.
（バロン）ソルヴァーであるジンが　ＰＯＧに
入るのは極めて異例のことでした。
It was exceptional that a Solver like Jin joined the POG.
「それだけ　ジンの能力は
比類なきものなのだ…」。
That only proved that his prowess was on a whole different level.
当時の私には　そんな認識しか
なかったのです。
That was the only way I could look at it back then.
ジンの成長を促すため
私は　彼の専属ギヴァーとして→
To aid Jin's progress, I was ordered to become his Giver and continue making puzzles for him.
パズルの作成を命じられました。
しかし　ジンは→
But Jin could no longer be satisfied with just that.
やがて　そんなものでは
満足できなくなっていったのです。
（バロン）
力を持て余した彼は　次第に→
He had too much energy left, so he kept on challenging more and more dangerous puzzles.
危険なパズルに挑戦するように
なっていきました。
（バロン）「賢者のパズル」です。
Sage Puzzles.
そんなある日のことでした。
彼が　未来を目にしたのは…。
Then one day, he saw the future.
（ジン）あれは…。
回想
Is that...
（ジン）うっ。　あはっ。
回想
ピ　ピタゴラス…　伯爵。
C-Count Pythagoras...
Don't be foolish!
回想　（バロン）バカなことを言うな！
（ジン）本当だ。
It's true.
回想　俺は確かに見たんだ。　ピタゴラス
伯爵が　この世界を滅ぼす未来を。
I saw it.
The future where Count Pythagoras destroys the world.
そんなもの　タダの幻だ！
回想
It was just an illusion!
伯爵は　神の書を
回想
輝かしい未来のために…。
The Count will use the Revelations for a brighter future!
Since ancient times, many people have sought the Revelations.
回想
古代より　あまたの者が
神の書を求めてきた。
回想
その力で　世界を
自らの手中に収めるためにな。
All just to hold the world in their hands.
伯爵も同じだ。
回想
しかし…。
The Count is no different.
But...
回想
バロン。　俺たちは
伯爵に　だまされてたんだよ！
Baron. The Count is lying to us!
俺はもう　パズルを捨てる。
回想
ジン！
I won't touch puzzles anymore.
Jin!
やつの思いどおりに
回想
させてたまるか！
I won't let him use me!
俺が　パズルを捨てれば
回想
それで済む話だ。
If I abandon puzzles, it'll all be over with.
しかし　ジン　お前…。
回想
But Jin, you're...
いいんだ。　これで　いいんだ。
It's okay. It's totally okay.
ビィーエ！
回想
おのれ　真方ジン。
Be cursed, Makata Jin.
（バロン）
伯爵の怒りは　すさまじかった。
The wrath of the Count was fearsome.
そして　それは　ジンの言葉の
正しさを証明していたのです。
That proved the truth of Jin's words.
I stayed with the POG anyway.
私はＰＯＧに残りました。
あえて…。
回想
（伯爵）ギヴァーとしての功績を
認め
セクションΦへの異動を命ずる。
I acknowledge your prowess as a Giver.
I've ordered your transfer to Section Phi.
回想
（バロン）ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
I will raise the Phi Brain for you.
回想　私の手で必ずや　ファイ・ブレインを
育ててごらんにいれます。
ならば　最初の任務だ。
回想
This will be your first mission then.
（伯爵）その子供を　お前に任せる。
I am placing that child in your care.
はい。
回想
Yes, sir.
あの子は？
回想
大門カイト。
That boy?
Daimon Kaito.
回想
お前と同じ　ファイ・ブレインの子供だ。
A child of the Phi Brain like you.
ファイ・ブレインの？
回想
あんな小さな子供がか？！
The Phi Brain?
A little kid like him?
彼は生まれたころから
回想
素質を見いだされ→
He has shown signs since he was born.
ＰＯＧの手によって
回想
育てられてきた。
He was raised by the POG.
彼の両親は？
回想
邪魔者は排除されたよ。
What about his parents?
The obstacles have been eliminated.
あっ！　それが　今
回想
お前のやっていることか。
Is that what you're doing now?
そうだ。
回想
Yes.
俺が　どんな思いで
回想
パズルを捨てたと思ってる？！
What do you think it felt like to abandon puzzles?!
それを　お前は！
回想
お前こそ…
俺の何が分かるというんだ！
What do you think you know about me?
（殴る音）
伯爵は　神の書を
回想
諦めたわけじゃない。
The Count has not given up on the Divine Revelations.
やつの野望を潰すためには
回想
俺が先に　神の書を手に入れ→
To thwart his plans, I will obtain the Divine Revelations first and erase it from this world.
この世から破棄する。
回想
それ以外に方法はない！
There is no other way.
俺たちは　あの子に
回想
未来を背負わせるしかないんだ。
We must make that child carry the future.
お前の気持ちも分かる。
回想
I understand how you feel.
あの子を見てると
回想
昔のお前を思い出すよ。
He reminds me of you when you were young.
回想
あの子も　パズルが大好きなんだ。
えっ？！
He loves puzzles too.
パズルなんて…。
回想
Who cares about...
（ジン）いいのか？！
回想
うっ。
Are you sure?
大好きだったんだろう。
回想
それまで手放して　いいのか？
You loved it. Do you really want to throw it away?
回想
そんなことをしても　大切なものを
失った悲しみからは逃げられない。
Even if you do that, you can't escape the pain of loss.
大切なものは手放すな。
回想
絶対に。
Don't let go of what's important.
Ever.
（バロン）
ジンは外側から　私は内側から→
Jin worked on the outside and I worked on the inside.
伯爵の野望をつぶすため
私たちは動き始めました。
We did what we could to thwart the Count's plans.
I can't defeat the Count as I am now.
回想
今の俺じゃ　伯爵には勝てない。
しかし　次　帰ってくる
回想
ときには　あの子に出番はない。
But when I get back, that boy won't have to step in the spotlight.
He set off on a long and dreadful journey of Fools' Puzzles.
（バロン）
ジンが向かったのは　長く険しい→
「愚者のパズル」巡礼の旅でした。
（伯爵）解道バロン　お前に
回想
セクションΦの総責任者の任を与える。→
Kaido Baron. I name you the chief supervisor of Section Phi.
回想　ところで最近「愚者のパズル」を
解放している者がいるそうだな。
By the way, there have been recent reports of someone solving Fools' Puzzles.
あのような敗北者
回想
気にかける価値もございません。
Madmen like that are of no worth to us.
よいことではないか。
回想
Are you certain about that?
（バロン）
真のファイ・ブレインは　私が育てます。
I will raise the true Phi Brain.
ジンはイギリスにも渡り　再びカイト君と
接触を果たしたといいます。
Jin returned to England and apparently met Kaito again.
そして　２年前。
Then two years ago...
（ジン）バロン。
回想
あっ。
Baron!
時は来た。
回想
The time has come.
ピタゴラス伯爵が　神のパズルの
場所を突き止めたようだ。
I heard Count Pythagoras has located the Divine Puzzle.
回想
あっ。　行くのか？
Are you going?
神のパズルは　ピタゴラスと俺が
回想
戦うことでしか解けない。
The Divine Puzzle can only be solved when Pythagoras and I fight.
そして生き残った者が
回想
神の書を手に入れることができる。
The one who survives will obtain the Divine Revelations.
（バロン）やつの力は強大だぞ。
回想
だろうな。
He is immensely powerful.
I guess.
回想
最終的に　１人が
犠牲にならないと　解けないパズル。
It's a puzzle where one of the challengers must die.
負ければ　お前の命は…。
回想
分かってる。
If you lose, you will...
I know.
Jin, I...
ジン。　私も…。
回想
ふっ。　バロン　お前には
お前の役目があるはずだ。
Baron, you have your own role.
私の…　役目？
回想
My role?
神の書を　この世から消し去る。
To erase the Divine Revelations.
回想
悲劇の連鎖を終わらせるんだ。
それだけが　俺の願いだ。
You will end the chain of tragedy.
That's all I ask for.
ジン。
回想
Jin...
これが　全ての顛末です。
This is where it all ends.
ちょっと待て！　ジンと伯爵の
勝負は　結局どうなったんだよ？
Wait! What happened in the fight between the Count and Jin?
分かりません。
分からねえって？！
I don't know.
How can you not know?
この日に関する記録は
全く残されていません。
There are no records whatsoever regarding that day.
でも　これだけは言えます。
But I can say one thing.
戦いの結果　ジンは心を奪われた。
Jin lost his heart in that fight.
And the Count has not appeared in front of anyone since then.
そして　伯爵もまた　その日以来
人前に姿を現さなくなりました。
He conveys his will only through Chief Rook.
今では　ルーク管理官を通して
その意思を伝えるのみです。
しかし　こうなった以上
伯爵の思惑も見えてきました。
Now I can see what the Count is speculating.
彼は　今度こそ
開くつもりなのです。
He wants to open it this time.
神のパズルへの扉を…
カイト君とルーク管理官を使って。
The gate to the Divine Puzzle...
By using Kaito and Chief Rook.
これで　ハッキリした！
Now I understand everything!
あいつは　やっぱり　ピタゴラス伯爵だ！
That's Count Pythagoras! He was pulling the strings this whole time!
全ての運命を操っていたのは
あいつだ！
If I defeat him, this'll all be over!
あいつを倒せば　全部終わる。
ちょっと待って！　もう一つ
隠しファイルがあるみたいだ。
Wait a second! There's a hidden file.
こ　これって？！
「ピタゴラス伯爵は死んだ？！」。
Count Pythagoras is dead?!
That can't be!
そんなバカな？！
じゃあ　今までＰＯＧを統率し→
Then who has been watching over and controlling the POG all this time?
指令を出していたのは
誰だって言うんだ？
ま　まさか？！
（ルーク）そう　そのまさかだ。
N-No way!
Yes, that's right.
ふっ。
ルーク管理官！
Chief Rook!
Why are you here?
お前　どうして　ここに？！
ピタゴラス伯爵は　もう居ないよ。
There is no Count Pythagoras anymore.
そのことを　カイトに
教えてあげようと思ってね。
I came to tell you that.
もう居ないって…。
つまり…。
What do you mean by that?
That means...
ピタゴラス伯爵は　半年前に死んだ。
Count Pythagoras died half a year ago.
I am the one who has absolute power over the POG.
現在　ＰＯＧの全権を
握っているのは　この僕だよ。
ルーク　お前…。
Rook...
What...
僕はね　もう　カイトに知られて
困ることなんて　何もないんだよ。
I don't want to keep anything else hidden from you.
僕の宝物…　カイトに見せてあげるよ。
I'll show you my little treasure now!
ジン！
この人が　真方ジン？！
Jin!
Is that Makata Jin?
ジン。
これが　僕のとっておきの財だよ。
Jin...
This is my hidden treasure.
ルーク　てめえ！
ほらほら　ダメじゃないか　カイト。
Rook, you bastard!
Oh my. This is no good, Kaito.
Huh?
あぁ？！
感情も　ろくに
制御できないようじゃ→
You can't even control your emotions properly.
腕輪の正当なる保有者とは
言えないな。
I can't really call you a true user of the Armband.
これじゃ　ジンも　がっかりだよ。
お前　何　言ってんだ！
Jin would be disappointed too.
What are you talking about?!
見せてあげる。
Let me show you.
That eye!
その目！
まさか　お前…。
Don't tell me!
そうだよ。　僕も
オルペウスの腕輪の契約者。
Yes. I am a contractor of an Armband of Orpheus as well.
ファイ・ブレインだ。
（４人）あっ？！
And a Phi Brain.
まさか…　ピタゴラス伯爵が
心の声
死んだって言うんなら…→
But then...
If Count Pythagoras is dead...
あれは…→
心の声
Who is...
あれは誰だ？
心の声
Who is that?
「おい！　お前」。
Hey, you!
「えっ？！」
「俺？！　どうして？」。
Me?! Why?!
tsukue no ue de umareta sekai
This world born on my table.
ichiban saki ni kimi ni misetakatta
I wanted you to see it first.
karappo no heya sotto nukedashite hashiri hajimeteta
I sneaked out of the empty room and started to run.
iki hazamasete oka wo noboru to
As I got to the top of the hill, out of breath,
kimi ga saki ni tsuite matteita ne
you were already there waiting for me.
takusan no hajimete kimi to mitsuketa takaramono datta
It was the first of many treasures we would find together.
kanashisa de afureta toki wa
When sorrow was overflowing in me,
nanimo iwazu ni tada soba ni ite kureta ne
you just silently stayed by my side.
ima de mo wasurenai yo
I still haven't forgotten that.
mata aou ne yakusoku wo shiyou
Let's promise we'll meet again.
kie wa shinai ano hi no sayonara
The goodbye of that day we'll never forget.
boku no subete kimi ga kureta michi
All I have I got from you,
zutto kokoro no naka hikaru yo
and it will all shine in my heart forever.